When thinking of giant animals, dinosaurs might be the first creatures you think of.
想到巨型动物时，恐龙可能是你最先想到的生物。
But before the dinosaurs became extinct, and before the first ever humans existed, there was megafauna.
但在恐龙灭绝之前，在第一批人类出现之前，存在过巨型动物。
In zoology, this means large animals.
在动物学中，这个词意味着大型动物。
One of the largest known mammals to have ever walked the Earth is the Paraceratherium – picture a gigantic hornless rhino, and you'll have a rough idea of what they looked like.
地球上已知最大的哺乳动物之一是副巨犀——想象一头巨大的无角犀牛，你就能大致了解它们的样子。
They lived around 25 million years ago and were most common in areas of the world that are now part of Asia, such as China, India and Kazakhstan.
它们生活在大约2500万年前，在现在属于亚洲的地区最为常见，如中国、印度和哈萨克斯坦。
From excavated fossils, these creatures are estimated to have been almost six metres tall – that's the height of two buses on top of each other!
根据出土的化石，这些生物估计有近六米高——相当于两辆公交车叠起来的高度！
And it's not just land enormous creatures lived on – they were in the skies and oceans too.
不仅陆地上有巨型生物——天空和海洋中也有。
The Argentavis is the largest flying bird to have been discovered.
阿根廷巨鸟是已发现的最大的飞鸟。
It lived until around six million years ago and had a wingspan of seven metres, over twice the size of the Andean condor, which is one of the largest birds on Earth today.
它生活在大约600万年前，翼展达七米，是当今地球上最大的鸟类之一安第斯神鹰的两倍多。
And we can't forget the giant shark that roamed the oceans, megalodon.
我们也不能忘记在海洋中漫游的巨齿鲨。
Imagine swimming in the sea and coming across an 18-metre-long shark!
想象一下在海里游泳时遇到一条18米长的鲨鱼！
Don't worry.
别担心。
They died out around 2.6 million years ago.
它们大约在260万年前灭绝了。
So, why were pre-historic animals so huge?
那么，为什么史前动物如此巨大呢？
There are a number of reasons.
原因有很多。
One is that, in the past, resources were more plentiful, so species were able to grow larger because they could eat more.
其一是过去资源更丰富，所以物种能够长得更大，因为它们可以吃得更多。
Scientists also believe that during certain periods of history, such as in the Carboniferous period, there were higher oxygen levels on Earth.
科学家还认为，在地球的某些历史时期，比如石炭纪，氧气含量更高。
At this time, some insects grew to the size of cars because of better oxygen delivery in their tracheal system, the network of tubes that enable insects to breathe.
当时，由于气管系统（使昆虫能够呼吸的管状网络）能更好地输送氧气，一些昆虫长到了汽车那么大。
Can you picture animals being so huge today?
你能想象今天的动物也如此巨大吗？